Travis Foster

2446 Morgans Point Dr., Dumfries, VA 22026 • Mobile: (703) 509-4401 • E-mail: tdf6n@virginia.edu • github.com/FosterTD

Objective

To be employed with a firm where I can apply technical experience to enhance business analytics that drive key management decision making. Over 10 years of experience in SQL, modeling, reporting, analyzing, and presenting recommendations to increase firm's key performance indicators. A team player who is attentive to detail and able to work in a fast-paced environment.

Education

Master of Business Administration, Business Analytics

George Mason University | GPA 3.8

Graduated: December 2021

Fairfax, Virginia

Bachelor of Arts: Economics

University of Virginia

Graduated: May 2009

Charlottesville, Virginia

Technical Experience

Advanced: SQL Query Writing, Dynamic SQL, Stored Procedures & Jobs, Functions, Triggers, SSIS Packages, SQL Profiler, SSRS, Power BI, SSAS Multidimensional Cubes & Administration, Visual Studio, Microsoft Excel-Advanced Modeling

Intermediate: Python – Data analysis via Pandas, Hadoop Hive, Apache Kylin, R Studio, MS Access, Tableau, GitHub

Professional Experience

Target Corporation May 2022 – Present

Senior Data Analyst, Finance Analytics and Automation

Remote

- Lead SSAS Multidimensional Cube reporting initiatives for sales and merchandise data for over 800 end users
- Create and migrate ETL actions using SQL and Python to assist with weekly data loads into SSAS Cubes
- Reconcile variances between source and SSAS Cubes using multiple SQL scripts and Microsoft Excel modeling
- Modify and maintain SSAS Multidimensional solution in Visual Studio and document updates using GitHub
- Train and mentor analysts on SQL query writing

Crowell & Moring LLP: Global Headquarters

December 2017 - May 2022

Manager of Data Analytics, Finance Department

Washington, District of Columbia

- Created and maintained automated SSIS ETL Packages for daily update of financial metrics and master data for employees and clients
- Created data marts using multiple sources such as Data Warehouses and external CSV files
- Created SQL scripts, triggers, stored procedures, and jobs to facilitate data processes for master employee and client data and firmwide financial metrics in data marts
- Created and documented Power BI dashboards using fact and dimension models for department reporting
- Created and maintained dimension and fact tables and multidimensional cubes for business reporting such as P/L statement and lawyer productivity
- Trained and mentored analysts and manage data architects on firm's database and reporting projects

Covington & Burling LLP: Global Headquarters

July 2015 - December 2017

Sr. Financial Analyst, Strategic Pricing Analytics Department

Washington, District of Columbia

- Created SQL scripts to extract historical timekeeper hours, rate, and billing data to determine client's realization rates
- Created Microsoft Excel models, using data extracts, to balance clients' risk/reward and maintaining firm's average gross margin
- Created SQL data extracts to analyze 900+ attorney's billing rates annually using statistical analyses in SQL Server and benchmarked to several market segmented legal industry surveys to justify annual rate increases
- Extracted client revenue data using SQL queries to obtain relevant financial data for client negotiations
- Collaborated with Marketing Department to cross-share information for AFA engagements and popular client solutions

Baker & McKenzie, LLP

April 2011 – July 2015

Financial and Budget Analyst, Accounting Department

Washington, District of Columbia

- Maintained monthly financial reporting using CSV files and Microsoft Excel reports, applying modeling skillset to build reports and source data quality checks to ensure accuracy
- Gathered requirements from business stakeholders to build SQL data extracts to analyze client's key performance indicators
- Maintained Microsoft Excel models for lawyer profit/loss data using SQL data extracts for revenue and expenses
- Monitored and analyzed budget to actuals for business department accounts using SQL scripts